<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>\n\n<rss version="2.0"\n xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"\n xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"\n xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"\n xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"\n xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"\n>\n\n<channel>\n<title>gr-qc updates on arXiv.org</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/</link>\n<description>General Relativity and Quantum Cosmology (gr-qc) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>\n<language>en-us</language>\n<pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 01:30:00 GMT</pubDate>\n<lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 20:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>\n<managingEditor>www-admin@arxiv.org</managingEditor>\n\n<image>\n<title>arXiv.org</title>\n<url>http://fr.arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/</link>\n</image>\n<item>\n<title>Thermodynamics of Charged, Rotating, and Accelerating Black Holes. (arXiv:1811.04936v1 [hep-th])</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.04936</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Anabalon_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andres Anabalon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Gray_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Finnian Gray&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Gregory_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruth Gregory&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Kubiznak_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David Kubiznak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Mann_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Robert B. Mann&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;We show how to obtain a consistent thermodynamic description of accelerating\nasymptotically AdS black holes, extending our previous results by including\ncharge and rotation. We find that the key ingredient of consistent\nthermodynamics is to ensure that the system is not over-constrained by\nincluding the possibility of varying the `string&apos; tensions that are responsible\nfor the acceleration of the black hole, yielding a first law of full\ncohomogeneity. The first law assumes the standard form, with the entropy given\nby one quarter of the horizon area and other quantities identified by standard\nmethods. In particular we compute the mass in two independent ways: through a\nEuclidean action calculation and by the method of conformal completion. The\nambiguity in the choice of the normalization of the timelike Killing vector can\nbe fixed by explicit coordinate transformation (in the case of rotation) to the\nstandard AdS form or by holographic methods (in the case of charge). This\nresolves a long-standing problem of formulating the thermodynamics of\naccelerating black holes, opening the way to detailed studies of their phase\nbehaviour.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.04936</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Axionic instabilities and new black hole solutions. (arXiv:1811.04945v1 [gr-qc])</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.04945</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Boskovic_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mateja Boskovic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Brito_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Richard Brito&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Cardoso_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vitor Cardoso&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Ikeda_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Taishi Ikeda&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Witek_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Helvi Witek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;The coupling between scalar and vector fields has a long and interesting\nhistory. Axions are one key possibility to solve the strong CP problem and\naxion-like particles could be one solution to the dark matter puzzle. Given the\nnature of the coupling, and the universality of free fall, nontrivial important\neffects are expected in regions where gravity is strong. Here, we show that\n&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;i. A background EM field induces an axionic instability in flat space, for\nlarge enough electric fields. Conversely, a homogeneous harmonic axion field\ninduces an instability in the Maxwell sector. When carried over to curved\nspacetime, this phenomena translates into generic instabilities of charged\nblack holes (BHs).\n&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;ii. In the presence of charge, BH uniqueness results are lost. We find\nsolutions which are small deformations of the Kerr-Newman geometry and hairy\nstationary solutions without angular momentum, which are `dragged&apos; by the\naxion. Axion fields must exist around spinning BHs if these are immersed in\nexternal magnetic fields. The axion profile can be obtained perturbatively from\nthe electro-vacuum solution derived by Wald.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;iii. Ultralight axions trigger superradiant instabilities of spinning BHs and\nform an axionic cloud in the exterior geometry. The superradiant growth can be\ninterrupted or suppressed through axionic or scalar couplings to EM. These\ncouplings lead to periodic bursts of light, which occur throughout the history\nof energy extraction from the BH. We provide numerical and simple analytical\nestimates for the rates of these processes.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;iv. Finally, we discuss how plasma effects can affect the evolution of\nsuperradiant instabilities.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.04945</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Analytic study of self-gravitating polytropic spheres with light rings. (arXiv:1811.04948v1 [gr-qc])</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.04948</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Hod_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shahar Hod&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;Ultra-compact objects describe horizonless solutions of the Einstein field\nequations which, like black-hole spacetimes, possess null circular geodesics\n(closed light rings). We study {\\it analytically} the physical properties of\nspherically symmetric ultra-compact isotropic fluid spheres with a polytropic\nequation of state. It is shown that these spatially regular horizonless\nspacetimes are generally characterized by two light rings\n$\\{r^{\\text{inner}}_{\\gamma},r^{\\text{outer}}_{\\gamma}\\}$ with the property\n${\\cal C}(r^{\\text{inner}}_{\\gamma})\\leq{\\cal C}(r^{\\text{outer}}_{\\gamma})$,\nwhere ${\\cal C}\\equiv m(r)/r$ is the dimensionless compactness parameter of the\nself-gravitating matter configurations. In particular, we prove that, while\nblack-hole spacetimes are characterized by the lower bound ${\\cal\nC}(r^{\\text{inner}}_{\\gamma})\\geq1/3$, horizonless ultra-compact objects may be\ncharacterized by the opposite dimensionless relation ${\\cal\nC}(r^{\\text{inner}}_{\\gamma})\\leq1/4$. Our results provide a simple analytical\nexplanation for the interesting numerical results that have recently presented\nby Novotn\\&apos;y, Hlad\\&apos;ik, and Stuchl\\&apos;ik [Phys. Rev. D 95, 043009 (2017)].\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.04948</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Electromagnetic emission from axionic clouds and the quenching of superradiant instabilities. (arXiv:1811.04950v1 [gr-qc])</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.04950</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Ikeda_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Taishi Ikeda&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Brito_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Richard Brito&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Cardoso_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vitor Cardoso&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;The nature of dark matter is one of the longest-standing puzzles in science.\nAxions or axion-like particles are a key possibility, and arise in mechanisms\nto solve the strong CP problem but also in low-energy limits of string theory.\nExtensive experimental and observational efforts are actively looking for\n`axionic&apos; imprints. Independently on their nature, their abundance, and on\ntheir contribution to the dark matter problem, axions form dense clouds around\nspinning black holes, grown by superradiant mechanisms. It was recently\nsuggested that once couplings to photons are considered, an exponential\n(quantum) stimulated emission of photons ensues at large enough axion number.\nHere we solve numerically the classical problem in different setups. We show\nthat laser-like emission from clouds exists at the classical level, and we\nprovide the first quantitative description of the problem.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.04950</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Generalized Hot Attractors. (arXiv:1811.04963v1 [hep-th])</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.04963</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Goldstein_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kevin Goldstein&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Jejjala_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vishnu Jejjala&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Mashiyane_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;James Junior Mashiyane&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Nampuri_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Suresh Nampuri&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;Non-extremal black holes are endowed with geometric invariants related to\ntheir horizon areas. We extend earlier work on hot attractor black holes to\nhigher dimensions and add a scalar potential. In addition to the event and\nCauchy horizons, when we complexify the radial coordinate, non-extremal black\nholes will generically have other horizons as well. We prove that the product\nof all of the horizon areas is independent of variations of the asymptotic\nmoduli further generalizing the attractor mechanism for extremal black holes.\nIn the presence of a scalar potential, as typically appears in gauged\nsupergravity, we find that the product of horizon areas is not necessarily the\ngeometric mean of the extremal area, however. We outline the derivation of\nhorizon invariants for stationary backgrounds.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.04963</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Effective sound speed in relativistic accretion discs around rotating black holes. (arXiv:1811.04975v1 [astro-ph.HE])</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.04975</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Maity_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Susovan Maity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Shaikh_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Md Arif Shaikh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Das_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tapas Kumar Das&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;For axially symmetric accretion maintained in the hydrostatic equilibrium\nalong the vertical direction in the Kerr metric, the radial Mach number does\nnot become unity at the critical point. The sonic points are, thus, formed at a\nradial distance different from that where the critical points are formed. We\npropose that a modified dynamical sound speed can be defined through the linear\nperturbation of the full space-time dependent equations describing the\naforementioned accretion flow structure. The linear stability analysis of such\nfluid equations leads to the formation of an wave equation which describes the\npropagation of linear acoustic perturbation. The speed of propagation of such\nperturbation can be used as the effective sound speed which makes the value of\nthe Mach number to be unity when evaluated at the critical points. This allows\nthe critical points to coalesce with the sonic points. We study how the spin\nangular momentum of the black hole (the Kerr parameter) influences the value of\nthe effective sound speed.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.04975</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Maximal Chaos from Strings, Branes and Schwarzian Action. (arXiv:1811.04977v1 [hep-th])</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.04977</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Banerjee_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Avik Banerjee&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Kundu_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arnab Kundu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Poojary_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rohan Poojary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;In this article, we explicitly demonstrate that, for a sufficiently generic\nclass of examples, an open string embedded in an AdS-background yields an\neffective Schwarzian action and, in the semi-classical description, the\nfluctuation modes of the open string couple to this Schwarzian sector. This\nleads to a maximal chaos, observed in the open string degrees of freedom,\nirrespective of the gravitational background. This corresponds to the dynamics\nof quark-like degrees of freedom in a strongly coupled large N_c gauge theory.\nWe also demonstrate a maximal chaos, resulting from an inherent D-brane\nhorizon, by computing the four-point out-of-time-ordered correlator of spin-one\noperators. We also offer some observations and comments regarding a class of\neffective theories that is described by a generic functional of a Schwarzian\nderivative.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.04977</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>More on Phase Transition and Renyi Entropy. (arXiv:1811.04980v1 [hep-th])</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.04980</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Ghodsi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ahmad Ghodsi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Qolibikloo_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Saeed Qolibikloo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;In this paper we study the scalar field condensation around the hyperbolic\nblack hole solutions in Einstein and Gauss-Bonnet gravities. We investigate\nRenyi entropy and the inequalities governing on it under this phase transition.\nOur numerical computations show that for positive values of Gauss-Bonnet\ncoupling and below the critical temperature one of these inequalities is\nviolated. This puts more restriction on the allowed values of Gauss-Bonnet\ncoupling.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.04980</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>On the detectability of ultralight scalar field dark matter with gravitational-wave detectors. (arXiv:1811.05003v1 [hep-ph])</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.05003</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Morisaki_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Soichiro Morisaki&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Suyama_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Teruaki Suyama&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;An ultralight scalar field is one of the dark matter candidates. If it\ncouples with Standard Model particles, it oscillates mirrors in\ngravitational-wave detectors and generates detectable signals. We study the\nspectra of the signals taking into account the motion of the detectors due to\nthe Earth&apos;s rotation/the detectors&apos; orbital motion around the Sun and formulate\na suitable data-analysis method to detect it. We find that our method can\nimprove the existing constraints given by fifth-force experiments on one of the\nscalar field&apos;s coupling constants by a factor of $\\sim 30$, $\\sim 100$ and\n$\\sim 350$ for $m_\\phi = 2 \\times 10^{-17}~\\mathrm{eV},~10^{-14}~\\mathrm{eV}$\nand $10^{-12}~\\mathrm{eV}$ respectively, where $m_\\phi$ is the scalar field&apos;s\nmass. Our study demonstrates that experiments with gravitational-wave detectors\nplay a complementary role to that Equivalence Principle tests do.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.05003</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Quantum cosmology of Eddington-Born-Infeld gravity fed by a scalar field: the big rip case. (arXiv:1811.05041v1 [gr-qc])</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.05041</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Albarran_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Imanol Albarran&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Bouhmadi_Lopez_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mariam Bouhmadi-L&amp;#xf3;pez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Chen_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Che-Yu Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Chen_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pisin Chen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;We study the quantum avoidance of the big rip singularity in the\nEddington-inspired-Born-Infeld (EiBI) phantom model. Instead of considering a\nsimple phantom dark energy component, which is described by a perfect fluid, we\nconsider a more fundamental degree of freedom corresponding to a phantom scalar\nfield with its corresponding potential, which would lead the classical universe\nto a big rip singularity. We apply a quantum geometrodynamical approach by\nperforming an appropriate Hamiltonian study including an analysis of the\nconstraints of the system. We then derive the Wheeler-DeWitt (WDW) equation and\nsee whether the solutions to the WDW equation satisfy the DeWitt boundary\ncondition. We find that by using a suitable Born-Oppenheimer (BO)\napproximation, whose validity is proven, the DeWitt condition is satisfied.\nTherefore, the big rip singularity is expected to be avoided in the quantum\nrealm.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.05041</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Monte Carlo simulation of cosmologies with dust. (arXiv:1811.05047v1 [gr-qc])</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.05047</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Ali_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Masooma Ali&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Hassan_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Syed Moeez Hassan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Husain_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Viqar Husain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;The quantum theory of the Friedmann cosmological model with dust and\ncosmological constant ($\\Lambda$) is not exactly solvable analytically. We\napply Path Integral Monte Carlo (PIMC) techniques to study its quantum dynamics\nusing the physical Hamiltonian corresponding to the dust field as a clock. We\nstudy (i) quantum fluctuations around classical paths and (ii) formulate the\nanalogues of the no-boundary and tunnelling proposals and simulate the ground\nstate wave functions. For $\\Lambda &amp;lt; 0$ a unique ground state wave function\nexists. For $\\Lambda &amp;gt; 0$ the physical Hamiltonian is not bounded below, but\nthe path integral for the propagator is convergent over a range of Euclidean\ntime $T$. We investigate the properties of the convergent propagator. The path\nintegral can be made convergent for all values of $T$ by restricting the\nintegral over paths with action greater than equal to zero. We explore the\nconsequences of such a choice.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.05047</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Micro black holes formed in the early Universe and their cosmological implications. (arXiv:1811.05049v1 [gr-qc])</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.05049</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Nakama_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tomohiro Nakama&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Yokoyama_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jun&amp;#x27;ichi Yokoyama&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;High energy collisions of particles may have created tiny black holes in the\nearly Universe, which might leave stable remnants instead of fully evaporating\nas a result of Hawking radiation. If the reheating temperature was sufficiently\nclose to the fundamental gravity scale, which can be different from the usual\nPlanck scale depending of the presence and properties of spatial\nextra-dimensions, the formation rate could have been sufficiently high and\nhence such remnants could account for the entire cold dark matter of the\nUniverse.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.05049</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Nonlinear stability of Minkowski spacetime in Nonlocal Gravity. (arXiv:1811.05117v1 [gr-qc])</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.05117</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Briscese_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fabio Briscese&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Modesto_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Leonardo Modesto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;We prove that the Minkowski spacetime is stable at nonlinear level and to all\nperturbative orders in the gravitational perturbation in a general class of\nnonlocal gravitational theories that are unitary and finite at quantum level.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.05117</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Holographic Renyi Entropy from Quantum Error Correction. (arXiv:1811.05171v1 [hep-th])</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.05171</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Akers_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chris Akers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Rath_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pratik Rath&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;We study Renyi entropies $S_n$ in quantum error correcting codes and compare\nthe answer to the cosmic brane prescription for computing $\\widetilde{S}_n\n\\equiv n^2 \\partial_n (\\frac{n-1}{n} S_n)$. We find that general operator\nalgebra codes have a similar, more general prescription. Notably, for the\nAdS/CFT code to match the specific cosmic brane prescription, the code must\nhave maximal entanglement within eigenspaces of the area operator. This gives\nus an improved definition of the area operator, and establishes a stronger\nconnection between the Ryu-Takayanagi area term and the edge modes in lattice\ngauge theory. We also propose a new interpretation of existing holographic\ntensor networks as area eigenstates instead of smooth geometries. This\ninterpretation would explain why tensor networks have historically had trouble\nmodeling the Renyi entropy spectrum of holographic CFTs, and it suggests a\nmethod to construct holographic networks with the correct spectrum.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.05171</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Particle creation in gravitational collapse to a horizonless compact object. (arXiv:1811.05179v1 [gr-qc])</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.05179</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Harada_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tomohiro Harada&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Cardoso_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vitor Cardoso&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Miyata_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daiki Miyata&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;Black holes (BHs) play a central role in physics. However, gathering\nobservational evidence for their existence is a notoriously difficult task.\nCurrent strategies to quantify the evidence for BHs all boil down to looking\nfor signs of highly compact, horizonless bodies. Here, we study particle\ncreation by objects which collapse to form ultra-compact configurations, with\nsurface at an areal radius $R=R_{f}$ satisfying $1-(2M/R_{f})= \\epsilon^{2}\\ll\n1$ with $M$ the object mass. We assume that gravitational collapse proceeds in\na `standard&apos; manner until $R=R_{f}+2M \\epsilon^{2\\beta}$, where $\\beta&amp;gt;0$, and\nthen slows down to form a static object of radius $R_{f}$. In the standard\ncollapsing phase, Hawking-like thermal radiation is emitted, which is as strong\nas the Hawking radiation of a BH with the same mass but lasts only for $\\sim\n40~(M/M_{\\odot})[44+\\ln (10^{-19}/\\epsilon)]~\\mu \\mbox{s}$. Thereafter, in a\nvery large class of models, there exist two bursts of radiation separated by a\nvery long dormant stage. The first burst occurs at the end of the transient\nHawking radiation, and is followed by a quiescent stage which lasts for $\\sim\n6\\times 10^{6}~(\\epsilon/10^{-19})^{-1}(M/M_{\\odot})~\\mbox{yr}$. Afterwards,\nthe second burst is triggered, after which there is no more particle production\nand the star is forever dark. In a model with $\\beta=1$, both the first and\nsecond bursts outpower the transient Hawking radiation by a factor $\\sim\n10^{38}(\\epsilon/10^{-19})^{-2}$.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.05179</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>BKL oscillations in 2+1 space-time dimensions. (arXiv:1811.05208v1 [gr-qc])</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.05208</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Fleig_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Philipp Fleig&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Belinski_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vladimir A. Belinski&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;We investigate the question whether there are cosmological models in 2+1\nspace-time dimensions which exhibit dynamics similar to BKL oscillations, as\nthe cosmological singularity is approached. Based on intuition, we conceive a\ntoy model which displays such oscillatory dynamics. We show that in the phase\nspace of this model, the cosmological singularity is represented by a\nseparatrix curve and discuss the model&apos;s dynamics within the cosmological\nbilliards picture. Finally, we offer a physical interpretation for a family of\nsimilar cosmological models in terms of the topological degrees of freedom of\ngravity in 2+1 dimensions.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.05208</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Kinematic and statistical inconsistencies of Ho$\\check{\\textrm{r}}$ava-Lifshitz cosmology. (arXiv:1811.05227v1 [gr-qc])</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.05227</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Luongo_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Orlando Luongo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Muccino_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marco Muccino&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Quevedo_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hernando Quevedo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;We investigate the validity of a \\emph{minimal} cosmological model derived\nfrom the renormalizable Ho$\\check{\\textrm{r}}$ava action at low redshift scales\nby using different cosmological and statistical tests. Assuming pure attractive\ngravity, i.e., $\\lambda&amp;gt;1/3$ in the Ho$\\check{\\textrm{r}}$ava action, we\ncompare the Union 2.1 supernova type Ia data with the kinematics following from\na model-independent approach. The two approaches, although compatible, lead to\nexplicit cosmographic constraints on the free parameters of the\nHo$\\check{\\textrm{r}}$ava action, which turn out to be in strong disagreement\nwith the $\\Lambda$CDM, $w$CDM and Chevallier-Polarski-Linder scenarios. To show\nthis, we use standard diagnostic tools of regression models, namely the Akaike\nand the Bayesian Information Criteria. Using such model-independent statistical\nmethods, we show that Ho$\\check{\\textrm{r}}$ava-Lifshitz cosmology differs from\nthe standard dark energy scenarios, \\emph{independently} of the number of free\nparameters involved in the model. Since this result is valid at small redshift\ndomains, it indicates the presence of inconsistencies in the minimal version of\nHo$\\check{\\textrm{r}}$ava-Lifshitz cosmology even at the level of background\ncosmology.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.05227</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>AdS gravity, SO(2,d) gauge theory and Holography. (arXiv:1811.05286v1 [hep-th])</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.05286</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Wang_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhao-Long Wang&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;Inspired by the general relation between the boundary global symmetry and the\nbulk gauge symmetry in AdS/CFT, we reformulate the d+1 dimensional AdS gravity\ntheory as a SO(2,d) gauge theory. In this formalism, the pull back of the bulk\nequation of motion onto a co-dimension one hypersurface \\Sigma can be naturally\nexplained as the SO(2,d) conservation law under a local energy scale of the\ndual CFT. Providing these conservation laws as well as a SO(2,d) covariant area\nlaw are valid for any local energy scale, the bulk Einstein equation will be\nautomatically implied.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.05286</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Some globally conserved currents from generalized Killing vectors and scalar test fields. (arXiv:1811.05312v1 [gr-qc])</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.05312</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Feng_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Justin C. Feng&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;In this article, I discuss the construction of some globally conserved\ncurrents that one can construct in the absence of a Killing vector. One is\nbased on the Komar current, which is constructed from an arbitrary vector field\nand has an identically vanishing divergence. I obtain some expressions for\nKomar currents constructed from some generalizations of Killing vectors which\nmay in principle be constructed in a generic spacetime. I then present an\nexplicit example for an outgoing Vaidya spacetime which demonstrates that the\nresulting Komar currents can yield conserved quantities that behave in a manner\nexpected for the energy contained in the outgoing radiation. Finally, I\ndescribe a method for constructing another class of (non-Komar) globally\nconserved currents using a scalar test field that satisfies an inhomogeneous\nwave equation, and discuss two examples; the first example may provide a useful\nframework for examining the arrow of time and its relationship to energy\nconditions, and the second yields (with appropriate initial conditions) a\nglobally conserved energy- and momentum- like quantity that measures the degree\nto which a given spacetime deviates from symmetry.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.05312</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Thermal fluctuations to thermodynamics of non-rotating BTZ black hole. (arXiv:1811.05313v1 [gr-qc])</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.05313</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Nadeem-ul-islam/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nadeem-ul-islam&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Ganai_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Prince A. Ganai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Upadhyay_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sudhaker Upadhyay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we discuss the effect of small statistical thermal\nfluctuations around the equilibrium on the thermodynamics of small non-rotating\nBTZ black hole. This is done by evaluating the leading-order corrections to the\nthermodynamical equation of states, namely, entropy, free energy, internal\nenergy, pressure, enthalpy, Gibbs free energy and specific heat quantitatively.\nIn order to analyse the effect of perturbations on the thermodynamics, we plot\nvarious graphs and compare corrected and non-corrected thermodynamic quantities\nwith respect to event horizon radius of non-rotating BTZ black hole. We also\nderive the first-order corrections to isothermal compressibility.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.05313</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Gravitational waves at their own gravitational speed. (arXiv:1811.05332v1 [gr-qc])</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.05332</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Unnikrishnan_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;C. S. Unnikrishnan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Gillies_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;George T. Gillies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;Gravitational waves propagate at the speed of light in general relativity,\nbecause of its special relativistic basis. However, light propagation is linked\nto the electromagnetic phenomena, with the permittivity and permeability\nconstants as the determining factors. Is there a deeper reason why waves in a\ngeometric theory of gravity propagate at a speed determined by electromagnetic\nconstants? What is the relation between gravity&apos;s own constants and the speed\nof gravitational waves? Our attempt to answer these fundamental questions takes\nus far and deep into the universe.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.05332</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>$\\kappa$-deformed BMS symmetry. (arXiv:1811.05360v1 [hep-th])</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.05360</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Borowiec_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Borowiec&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Brocki_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;L. Brocki&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Kowalski_Glikman_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Kowalski-Glikman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Unger_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Unger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;We present the quantum $\\kappa$-deformation of BMS symmetry, by generalizing\nthe lightlike $\\kappa$-Poincar\\&apos;e Hopf algebra. On the technical level our\nanalysis relies on the fact that the lightlike $\\kappa$-deformation of\nPoincar\\&apos;e algebra is given by a twist and the lightlike deformation of any\nalgebra containing Poincar\\&apos;e as a subalgebra can be done with the help of the\nsame twisting element. We briefly comment on the physical relevance of the\nobtained $\\kappa$-BMS Hopf algebra as a possible asymptotic symmetry of quantum\ngravity.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.05360</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Stealth Schwarzschild-(A)dS black hole in DHOST theories after GW170817: Linear time-dependent scalar dressing. (arXiv:1811.05369v1 [gr-qc])</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.05369</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Achour_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jibril Ben Achour&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Liu_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hongguang Liu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;Extensions of General Relativity (GR) face the challenging task to modify\ngravity on large scale while restoring GR predictions on scales in which the\ntheory is experimentally confirmed, typically for the local tests within the\nsolar system. In this regard, stealth black hole solutions provide an\ninteresting path to discuss the viability of any extension of GR on local\nscales. For scalar-tensor extensions, such black hole configurations correspond\nto vacuum solutions of GR and admit a scalar dressing which does not gravitate,\nrevealing itself only at the perturbative level. It was recently shown that the\nsubclass of Horndeski, consistent with the recent observational constraint\n$c_{\\text{grav}}=c_{\\text{light}}$, does not admit such configuration when the\nscalar field is time-dependent. In this letter, we scan the viable degenerate\nhigher order scalar tensor (DHOST) theories satisfying the constraint\n$c_{\\text{grav}}=c_{\\text{light}}$ and derive the conditions on the Lagrangian\nof this theory to admit a stealth Schwarzschild-(A)dS solution dressed with a\nlinear time-dependent scalar field, and assuming a constant kinetic term. As a\nby-product, we show that the subclass of the Gleyzes-Langlois-Piazza-Vernizzi\n(GLPV) theory satisfying $c_{\\text{grav}}=c_{\\text{light}}$ admits a pure\nSchwarzschild solution but not its (A)dS extension, at least for our specific\nscalar profil, generalizing previous result on stealth black hole solutions in\nthe Horndeski subclass.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.05369</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Horndeski gravity without screening in binary pulsars. (arXiv:1811.05393v1 [astro-ph.HE])</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.05393</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Dyadina_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;P.I.Dyadina&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Avdeev_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;N.A.Avdeev&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Alexeyev_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S.O.Alexeyev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;We test the subclasses of Horndeski gravity without Vainshtein mechanism in\nthe strong field regime of binary pulsars. We find the rate of energy losses\nvia the gravitational radiation predicted by such theories and compare our\nresults with observational data from quasi-circular binaries PSR J1738+0333,\nPSR J0737-3039, PSR J1012+5307. In addition, we consider few specific cases:\nthe hybrid metric-Palatini f(R)-gravity and massive Brans-Dicke theory.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.05393</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>4D spin-2 fields from 5D Chern-Simons theory. (arXiv:1811.05435v1 [gr-qc])</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.05435</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Albornoz_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;N.L. Gonz&amp;#xe1;lez Albornoz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Lust_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dieter Lust&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Salgado_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Salgado&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Schmidt_May_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Angnis Schmidt-May&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;We consider a 5-dimensional Chern-Simons gauge theory for the isometry group\nof Anti-de-Sitter spacetime,\n$\\operatorname{AdS}_{4+1}\\simeq\\operatorname{SO}(4,2)$, and invoke different\ndimensional reduction schemes in order to relate it to 4-dimensional spin-2\ntheories. The AdS gauge algebra is isomorphic to a parametrized 4-dimensional\nconformal algebra, and the gauge fields corresponding to the generators of\nnon-Abelian translations and special conformal transformations reduce to two\nvierbein fields in $D=4$. Besides these two vierbeine, our reduction schemes\nleave only the Lorentz spin connection as an additional dynamical field in the\n4-dimensional theories. We identify the corresponding actions as particular\ngeneralizations of Einstein-Cartan theory, conformal gravity and ghost-free\nbimetric gravity in first-order form.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.05435</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Relativistic cosmological large scale structures at one-loop. (arXiv:1811.05452v1 [astro-ph.CO])</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.05452</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Castiblanco_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lina Castiblanco&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gannouji_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Radouane Gannouji&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Norena_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jorge Nore&amp;#xf1;a&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Stahl_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cl&amp;#xe9;ment Stahl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;The large scale structure bispectrum in the squeezed limit couples large with\nsmall scales. Since relativity is important at large scales and non-linear loop\ncorrections are important at small scales, the proper calculation of the\nobserved bispectrum in this limit requires a non-linear relativistic\ncalculation. We compute the matter bispectrum in general relativity in the weak\nfield approximation. The calculation is as involved as existing second-order\nresults. We find several differences with the Newtonian calculation such as the\nnon-cancellation of IR divergences, the need to renormalize the background, and\nthe fact that initial conditions must be set at second order in perturbation\ntheory. For the bispectrum, we find relativistic corrections to be as large as\nthe newtonian result in the squeezed limit. In that limit relativistic one-loop\ncontributions, which we compute for the first time, can be as large as tree\nlevel results and have the same $1/k^2$ dependence as a primordial local\nnon-Gaussianity signal where $k$ is the momentum approaching zero. Moreover, we\nfind the time dependence of the relavistic corrections to the bispectrum to be\nthe same as that of a primordial non-Gaussianity signal.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.05452</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Imprints of local lightcone projection effects on the galaxy bispectrum IV: Second-order vector and tensor contributions. (arXiv:1811.05458v1 [astro-ph.CO])</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.05458</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Jolicoeur_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sheean Jolicoeur&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Allahyari_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alireza Allahyari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Clarkson_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chris Clarkson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Larena_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Julien Larena&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Umeh_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Obinna Umeh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Maartens_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Roy Maartens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;The galaxy bispectrum on scales around and above the equality scale receives\ncontributions from relativistic effects. Some of these arise from lightcone\ndeformation effects, which come from local and line-of-sight integrated\ncontributions. Here we calculate the local contributions from the generated\nvector and tensor background which is formed as scalar modes couple and enter\nthe horizon. We show that these modes are sub-dominant when compared with other\nrelativistic contributions.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.05458</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>The maximal existence region of the analytic solutions for a class of characteristic Einstein vacuum equations. (arXiv:1610.06025v2 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1610.06025</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Caciotta_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G.Caciotta&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Nicolo_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F.Nicol&amp;#xf2;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;The main goal of this work consists in showing that the analytic solutions\nfor a class of characteristic problems for the Einstein vacuum equations have\nan existence region larger than the one provided by the Cauchy-Kowalevski\ntheorem, due to the intrinsic hyperbolicity of the Einstein equations. The\nmagnitude of this region depends only on suitable $H_s$ Sobolev norms of the\ninitial data for a fixed $s\\leq 7$ and if the initial data are sufficiently\nsmall the analytic solution is global. In a previous paper, hereafter &quot;I&quot;, we\nhave described a geometric way of writing the vacuum Einstein equations for the\ncharacteristic problems we are considering and a local solution in a suitable\n&quot;double null cone gauge&quot; characterized by the use of a double null cone\nfoliation of the spacetime.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1610.06025</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>More on cold dark matter from q-theory. (arXiv:1612.04235v3 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1612.04235</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Klinkhamer_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F.R. Klinkhamer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Volovik_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G.E. Volovik&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;We consider the rapidly-oscillating part of a $q$-field in a cosmological\ncontext and find that its energy density behaves in the same way as a\ncold-dark-matter component, namely proportional to the inverse cube of the\ncosmic scale factor.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1612.04235</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Antimatter and the second law of thermodynamics. (arXiv:1704.01750v3 [hep-th] UPDATED)</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1704.01750</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Etesi_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gabor Etesi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;In this letter we make a proposal that the second law of thermodynamics holds\ntrue for a closed physical system consisting of pure antimatter in the\nthermodynamical limit, but in a reversed form. We give two plausible arguments\nin favour to this proposal: one is based on the CPT theorem of relativistic\nquantum field theories while the other one is refers Noether&apos;s theorem of\ntheoretical physics. However in our understanding the ultimate validity or\ninvalidity of this idea can be decided only by future physical experiments.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;As a consequence of the proposal we argue that the dynamical evolution of\npure macroscopic antimatter systems can be very different from that of ordinary\nmatter systems in the sense that sufficiently massive antimatter systems could\nhave stronger tendency to form black holes during time evolution than their\nordinary counterparts. Taking into account the various &quot;no-hair&quot; theorems in\nblack hole physics as well, as a result, antimatter could tracelessly disappear\nbehind black hole event horizons faster in time than ordinary matter. The\nobserved asymmetry of matter and antimatter could then be explained even if\ntheir presence in the Universe was symmetric in the beginning.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1704.01750</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>The massive Dirac equation in the curved spacetime of the Kerr-Newman (anti) de Sitter black hole. (arXiv:1801.03157v4 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1801.03157</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Kraniotis_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G. V. Kraniotis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;Exact solutions of the Dirac general relativistic equation that describe the\ndynamics of a massive, electrically charged with half integer spin particle in\nthe curved spacetime geometry of an electrically charged, rotating\nKerr-Newman-(anti) de Sitter black hole are investigated. We first, derive the\nDirac equation in the Kerr-Newman-de Sitter (KNdS) black hole background using\na generalised Kinnersley null tetrad in the Newman-Penrose formalism.\nSubsequently in this frame and in the KNdS black hole spacetime, we prove the\nseparation of the Dirac equation into ordinary differential equations for the\nradial and angular parts. Under specific transformations of the independent and\ndependent variables we prove that the transformed radial equation for a massive\ncharged spin $\\frac{1}{2}$ fermion in the background KNdS black hole\nconstitutes a highly non-trivial generalisation of Heun&apos;s equation since it\npossess five regular finite singular points. Using a Regge-Wheeler-like\nindependent variable we transform the radial equation in the KNdS background\ninto a Schr\\&quot;{o}dinger like differential equation and investigate its\nasymptotic behaviour near the event and cosmological horizons. For the case of\na massive fermion in the background of a Kerr-Newman (KN) black hole we first\nprove that the radial and angular equations that result from the separation of\nDirac&apos;s equation reduce to the generalised Heun differential equation (GHE).\nThe local solutions of such GHE are derived and can be described by holomorphic\nfunctions whose power series coefficients are determined by a four-term\nrecurrence relation. In addition using asymptotic analysis we derive the\nsolutions for the massive fermion far away from the KN black hole and the\nsolutions near the event horizon . The determination of the separation constant\nas an eigenvalue problem in the KN background is investigated.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1801.03157</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Symbolic tensor calculus on manifolds: a SageMath implementation. (arXiv:1804.07346v2 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1804.07346</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Gourgoulhon_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Eric Gourgoulhon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Mancini_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marco Mancini&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;These lecture notes present a method for symbolic tensor calculus that (i)\nruns on fully specified smooth manifolds (described by an atlas), (ii) is not\nlimited to a single coordinate chart or vector frame, (iii) runs even on\nnon-parallelizable manifolds and (iv) is independent of the symbolic backend\nused to perform calculus at the level of coordinate expressions. In addition to\nthe main ideas, we discuss some details of the implementation in the\nopen-source mathematics software system SageMath, which has been performed via\nthe SageManifolds project.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1804.07346</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Unruh effect for interacting particles with ultracold atoms. (arXiv:1804.11323v3 [cond-mat.quant-gas] UPDATED)</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1804.11323</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Kosior_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arkadiusz Kosior&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Lewenstein_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maciej Lewenstein&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Celi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alessio Celi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;The Unruh effect is a quantum relativistic effect where the accelerated\nobserver perceives the vacuum as a thermal state. Here we propose the\nexperimental realization of the Unruh effect for interacting ultracold fermions\nin optical lattices by a sudden quench resulting in vacuum acceleration with\nvarying interactions strengths in the real temperature background. We observe\nthe inversion of statistics for the low lying excitations in the Wightman\nfunction as a result of competition between the spacetime and BCS Bogoliubov\ntransformations. This paper opens up new perspectives for simulators of quantum\ngravity.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1804.11323</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Holographic Thermodynamics of Accelerating Black Holes. (arXiv:1805.02687v2 [hep-th] UPDATED)</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1805.02687</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Anabalon_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andres Anabalon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Appels_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael Appels&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Gregory_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruth Gregory&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Kubiznak_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David Kubiznak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Mann_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Robert B. Mann&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Ovgun_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ali &amp;#xd6;vg&amp;#xfc;n&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;We present a careful study of accelerating black holes in anti-de Sitter\nspacetime, formulating the thermodynamics and resolving discrepancies that have\nappeared in previous investigations of the topic. We compute the dual\nstress-energy tensor for the spacetime and identify the energy density\nassociated with a static observer at infinity. The dual energy-momentum tensor\ncan be written as a three-dimensional perfect fluid plus a non-hydrodynamic\ncontribution with a universal coefficient which is given in gauge theory\nvariables. We demonstrate that both the holographic computation and the method\nof conformal completion yield the same result for the mass. We compare to\nprevious work on black funnels and droplets, showing that the boundary region\ncan be endowed with non-compact geometry, and comment on this novel holographic\ndual geometry.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1805.02687</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Higher Order Clockwork Gravity. (arXiv:1805.03523v2 [hep-th] UPDATED)</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1805.03523</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Niedermann_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Florian Niedermann&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Padilla_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Antonio Padilla&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Saffin_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Paul M. Saffin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;We present a higher order generalisation of the clockwork mechanism starting\nfrom an underlying non-linear multigravity theory with a single scale and\nnearest neighbour ghost-free interactions. Without introducing any hierarchies\nin the underlying potential, this admits a family of Minkowski vacua around\nwhich massless graviton fluctuations couple to matter exponentially more weakly\nthan the heavy modes. Although multi-diffeomorphisms are broken to the diagonal\nsubgroup in our theory, an asymmetric distribution of conformal factors in the\nbackground vacua translates this diagonal symmetry into an asymmetric shift of\nthe graviton gears. In particular we present a TeV scale multigravity model\nwith ${\\cal O}(10)$ sites that contains a massless mode whose coupling to\nmatter is Planckian, and a tower of massive modes starting at a TeV mass range\nand with TeV strength couplings. This suggests a possible application to the\nhierarchy problem as well as a candidate for dark matter.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1805.03523</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Spatially covariant gravity with velocity of the lapse function: the Hamiltonian analysis. (arXiv:1806.02811v3 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1806.02811</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Gao_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xian Gao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Yao_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhi-Bang Yao&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;We investigate a large class of gravity theories that respect spatial\ncovariance, and involve kinetic terms for both the spatial metric and the lapse\nfunction. Generally such kind of theories propagate a ghost mode. Through a\ndetailed Hamiltonian analysis, we find that the condition requiring the kinetic\nterms to be degenerate is not sufficient to evade the ghost mode in general.\nThis is because the primary constraint due to the degeneracy condition does not\nnecessarily induce a secondary constraint, if the mixings between temporal and\nspatial derivatives are present. In this case, the second condition that we dub\nas the consistency condition must be imposed in order to ensure the existence\nof the secondary constraint and thus to remove the ghost mode. We also show how\nour formalism works through an explicit example, in which the degeneracy\ncondition is not sufficient and thus the consistency condition must be imposed.\nBy employing the Stueckelberg trick, our formalism provides us a much broader\nframework for healthy generally covariant scalar-tensor theories.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1806.02811</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Exact black holes in quadratic gravity with any cosmological constant. (arXiv:1806.09516v2 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1806.09516</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Svarc_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Robert Svarc&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Podolsky_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiri Podolsky&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Pravda_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vojtech Pravda&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Pravdova_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alena Pravdova&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;We present a new explicit class of black holes in general quadratic gravity\nwith a cosmological constant. These spherically symmetric\nSchwarzschild-Bach-(anti-)de Sitter geometries (Schwa-Bach-(A)dS), derived\nunder the assumption of constant scalar curvature, form a three-parameter\nfamily determined by the black-hole horizon position, the value of Bach\ninvariant on the horizon, and the cosmological constant. Using a conformal to\nKundt metric ansatz, the fourth-order field equations simplify to a compact\nautonomous system. Its solutions are found as power series, enabling us to\ndirectly set the Bach parameter and/or cosmological constant equal to zero. To\ninterpret these spacetimes, we analyse the metric functions. In particular, we\ndemonstrate that for a certain range of positive cosmological constant there\nare both black-hole and cosmological horizons, with a static region between\nthem. The tidal effects on free test particles and basic thermodynamic\nquantities are also determined.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1806.09516</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Dynamical analysis of Brans-Dicke Universe with inverse power-law effective potential. (arXiv:1807.00987v2 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1807.00987</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Sim_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jonghyun Sim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Park_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiwon Park&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Lee_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tae Hoon Lee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;We study Brans-Dicke cosmology with an inverse power-law effective potential.\nBy using dynamical analyses, we search for fixed points corresponding to the\nradiation-like matter and dark energy-dominated era of our Universe, and the\nstability of fixed points is also investigated. We find phase space\ntrajectories which are attracted to the stable point of the dark\nenergy-dominated era from unstable fixed points like matter-dominated era of\nthe Universe. The dark energy comes from effective potentials of the\nBrans-Dicke field, whose variation (related to the time-variation of the\ngravitational coupling constant) is shown to be in good agreement with\nobservational data.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1807.00987</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Schwinger Effect in Inflaton-Driven Electric Field. (arXiv:1807.03753v2 [hep-th] UPDATED)</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1807.03753</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Kitamoto_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hiroyuki Kitamoto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;In a four dimensional inflation theory, a persistent electric field can be\nestablished by making the inflaton coupled to the gauge field like a dilaton.\nWe investigate the pair production of scalar particles in the inflaton-driven\nelectric field. In particular, we evaluate the induced current due to the pair\nproduction. The presence of the dilatonic coupling ensures the validity of the\nWKB approximation at the past and the future infinities, without tuning\nconstant parameters. Thus, the semiclassical description is applicable in\nevaluating the induced current. Solving the field equations with the induced\ncurrent, we evaluate the first-order backreaction to the electric field. It\nturns out that the electric field decreases with the cosmic expansion. The\nresult indicates that the no-anisotropic hair theorem for inflation holds true\nregardless of whether the dilatonic coupling is present or not.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1807.03753</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Spectral lines of extreme compact objects. (arXiv:1807.04762v2 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1807.04762</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Macedo_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Caio F. B. Macedo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Stratton_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tom Stratton&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Dolan_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sam Dolan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Crispino_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lu&amp;#xed;s C. B. Crispino&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;We study the absorption of scalar fields by extreme/exotic compact objects\n(ECOs) -- horizonless alternatives to black holes -- via a simple model in\nwhich dissipative mechanisms are encapsulated in a single parameter. Trapped\nmodes, localized between the ECO core and the potential barrier at the\nphotosphere, generate Breit-Wigner-type spectral lines in the absorption cross\nsection. Absorption is enhanced whenever the wave frequency resonates with a\ntrapped mode, leading to a spectral profile which differs qualitatively from\nthat of a black hole. We introduce a model based on Nariai spacetime, in which\nproperties of the spectral lines are calculated in closed form. We present\nnumerically calculated absorption cross sections and transmission factors for\nexample scenarios, and show how the Nariai model captures the essential\nfeatures. We argue that, in principle, ECOs can be distinguished from black\nholes through their absorption spectra.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1807.04762</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Quantum Circuit Model of Black Hole Evaporation. (arXiv:1807.07672v2 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1807.07672</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Tokusumi_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tomoro Tokusumi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Matsumura_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Akira Matsumura&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Nambu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yasusada Nambu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;We consider a quantum circuit model describing the evaporation process of\nblack holes. We specifically examine the behavior of the multipartite\nentanglement represented by this model, and find that the entanglement\nstructure depends on the black hole mass $M$ and the frequency of the Hawking\nradiation $\\omega$. For sufficiently small values of $M\\omega$, the black hole\nand the radiation system becomes a separable state after the Page time and a\nfirewall-like structure appears. On the contrary, for larger values of\n$M\\omega$, the entanglement between the black hole and the radiation is not\nlost. These behaviors imply that owing to the monogamy property of the\nmultipartite entanglement, low frequency modes of the Hawking radiation\ndestroys the quantum correlation between the black hole and the emitted Hawking\nradiation.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1807.07672</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Simulating the Magnetorotational Collapse of Supermassive Stars: Incorporating Gas Pressure Perturbations and Different Rotation Profiles. (arXiv:1807.07970v3 [astro-ph.HE] UPDATED)</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1807.07970</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Sun_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lunan Sun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ruiz_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Milton Ruiz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Shapiro_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stuart L. Shapiro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;Collapsing supermassive stars (SMSs) with masses $M \\gtrsim 10^{4-6}M_\\odot$\nhave long been speculated to be the seeds that can grow and become supermassive\nblack holes (SMBHs). We previously performed GRMHD simulations of marginally\nstable magnetized $\\Gamma = 4/3$ polytropes uniformly rotating at the\nmass-shedding limit to model the direct collapse of SMSs. These configurations\nare supported entirely by thermal radiation pressure and model SMSs with $M\n\\gtrsim 10^{6}M_\\odot$. We found that around $90\\%$ of the initial stellar mass\nforms a spinning black hole (BH) surrounded by a massive, hot, magnetized\ntorus, which eventually launches an incipient jet. Here we perform GRMHD\nsimulations of $\\Gamma \\gtrsim 4/3$, polytropes to account for the perturbative\nrole of gas pressure in SMSs with $M \\lesssim 10^{6}M_\\odot$. We also consider\ndifferent initial stellar rotation profiles. The stars are initially seeded\nwith a dynamically weak dipole magnetic field that is either confined to the\nstellar interior or extended from its interior into the stellar exterior. We\nfind that the mass of the BH remnant is $90\\%-99\\%$ of the initial stellar\nmass, depending sharply on $\\Gamma -4/3$ as well as on the initial stellar\nrotation profile. After $t\\sim 250-550M\\approx 1-2\\times 10^3(M/10^6M_\\odot)$s\nfollowing the BH formation, a jet is launched and it lasts for $\\sim\n10^4-10^5(M/10^6M_\\odot)$s, consistent with the duration of long gamma-ray\nbursts. Our results suggest that the Blandford-Znajek mechanism powers the jet.\nThey are also in agreement with our proposed universal model that estimates\naccretion rates and luminosities that characterize magnetized BH-disk remnant\nsystems that launch a jet. This model helps explain why the outgoing\nluminosities for vastly different BH-disk formation scenarios all reside within\na narrow range ($\\sim 10^{52 \\pm 1} \\rm erg/s$), roughly independent of $M$.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1807.07970</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Symmetries and charges of general relativity at null boundaries. (arXiv:1807.11499v2 [hep-th] UPDATED)</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1807.11499</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Chandrasekaran_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Venkatesa Chandrasekaran&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Flanagan_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Eanna E. Flanagan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Prabhu_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kartik Prabhu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;We study general relativity at a null boundary using the covariant phase\nspace formalism. We define a covariant phase space and compute the algebra of\nsymmetries at the null boundary by considering the boundary-preserving\ndiffeomorphisms that preserve this phase space. This algebra is the semi-direct\nsum of diffeomorphisms on the two sphere and a nonabelian algebra of\nsupertranslations that has some similarities to supertranslations at null\ninfinity. By using the general prescription developed by Wald and Zoupas, we\nderive the localized charges of this algebra at cross sections of the null\nsurface as well as the associated fluxes. Our analysis is covariant and applies\nto general non-stationary null surfaces. We also derive the global charges that\ngenerate the symmetries for event horizons, and show that these obey the same\nalgebra as the linearized diffeomorphisms, without any central extension. Our\nresults show that supertranslations play an important role not just at null\ninfinity but at all null boundaries, including non-stationary event horizons.\nThey should facilitate further investigations of whether horizon symmetries and\nconservation laws in black hole spacetimes play a role in the information loss\nproblem, as suggested by Hawking, Perry, and Strominger.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1807.11499</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Vacuum polarization on topological black holes. (arXiv:1808.04386v2 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1808.04386</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Morley_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thomas Morley&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Taylor_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Peter Taylor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Winstanley_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Elizabeth Winstanley&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;We investigate quantum effects on topological black hole space-times within\nthe framework of quantum field theory on curved space-times. Considering a\nquantum scalar field, we extend a recent mode-sum regularization prescription\nfor the computation of the renormalized vacuum polarization to asymptotically\nanti-de Sitter black holes with nonspherical event horizon topology. In\nparticular, we calculate the vacuum polarization for a massless,\nconformally-coupled scalar field on a four-dimensional topological\nSchwarzschild-anti-de Sitter black hole background, comparing our results with\nthose for a spherically-symmetric black hole.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1808.04386</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Traversable Wormholes as Quantum Channels: Exploring CFT Entanglement Structure and Channel Capacity in Holography. (arXiv:1808.05963v2 [hep-th] UPDATED)</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1808.05963</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Bao_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ning Bao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Chatwin_Davies_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aidan Chatwin-Davies&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Pollack_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jason Pollack&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Remmen_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Grant N. Remmen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;We interpret the traversable wormhole in AdS/CFT in the context of quantum\ninformation theory. In particular, we investigate its properties as both a\nquantum channel and entanglement witness. We define protocols that allow either\nthe bounding of the channel&apos;s entanglement capacity or the determination of\naspects of the entanglement structure between the two boundary CFTs. Such\nprotocols and connections allow for the use of quantum channel techniques in\nthe study of gravitational physics and vice versa. More generally, our results\nsuggest a purely quantum information-theoretic criterion for recognizing when\nthe product of two boundary theories has a classical bulk interpretation.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1808.05963</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Parameterized Post-Einsteinian Gravitational Waveforms in Various Modified Theories of Gravity. (arXiv:1809.00259v2 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1809.00259</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Tahura_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sharaban Tahura&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Yagi_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kent Yagi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;Despite the tremendous success of general relativity so far, modified\ntheories of gravity have received increased attention lately, motivated from\nboth theoretical and observational aspects. Gravitational wave observations\nopened new possibilities for testing the viability of such theories in the\nstrong-field regime. One could test each theory against observed data one at a\ntime, though a more efficient approach would be to first probe gravity in a\ntheory-agnostic way and map such information to that on specific theories\nafterward. One example of such model-independent tests with gravitational waves\nis the parameterized post-Einsteinian formalism, where one introduces generic\nparameters in the amplitude and phase that capture non-Einsteinian effects. In\nthis paper, we derive gravitational waveforms from inspiraling compact binaries\nin various modified theories of gravity that violate at least one fundamental\npillar in general relativity. We achieve this by deriving relations between\ncorrections to the waveform amplitude/phase and those to the frequency\nevolution and Kepler&apos;s third law, since the latter two have already been (or\ncan easily be) derived in many theories. Such an analysis allows us to derive\ncorrections to the waveform amplitude, which extends many of previous works\nthat focused on phase corrections only. Moreover, we derive gravitational\nwaveforms in theories with varying gravitational constant. We extend the\nprevious work by introducing two gravitational constants (the conservative one\nentering in the binding energy and the dissipative one entering in the\ngravitational wave luminosity) and allowing masses of binary constituents to\nvary with time. We also correct some errors in previous literature. Our results\ncan be used to improve current analyses of testing general relativity as well\nas to achieve new projected constraints on many modified theories of gravity.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1809.00259</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>The geometric challenge of testing gravity with wide binaries. (arXiv:1810.13397v2 [astro-ph.SR] UPDATED)</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1810.13397</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+El_Badry_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kareem El-Badry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;Wide binaries provide promising laboratories for testing general relativity\n(GR) in the low-acceleration regime. Recent observational studies have found\nthat the difference in the proper motions and/or radial velocities of the\ncomponents of nearby wide binaries appear larger than predicted by Kepler&apos;s\nlaw&apos;s, indicating a potential breakdown of GR at low accelerations. These\nstudies have not accounted for projection effects owing to the different\nposition of the two stars on the celestial sphere. I show that two stars in a\nwide binary with identical 3D space velocities often have significantly\ndifferent proper motions and radial velocities purely due to projection\neffects. I construct a sample of simulated binaries that follow Kepler&apos;s laws\nand have similar phase-space distributions to the observed samples of nearby\nbinaries. Beyond separations of $\\sim$0.1 pc, direct comparison of the\ncomponents&apos; proper motions would suggest strong tensions with GR, even though\nthe simulated binaries follow Kepler&apos;s laws by construction. The magnitude of\nthe apparent disagreement is similar to that found observationally, suggesting\nthat the apparent tension between observations and GR may largely be due to\nprojection effects. I discuss prospects for constraining gravity at low\naccelerations with wide binaries. Robust tests of GR are possible with current\ndata but require measurements of 3D velocities. Further work is also needed to\nmodel contamination from unbound moving groups and unrecognized hierarchical\ntriples.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1810.13397</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Pressure effects in the weak-field limit of f(R) = R + alpha R^2 gravity. (arXiv:1811.01322v2 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.01322</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Sbisa_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fulvio Sbis&amp;#xe0;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Piattella_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Oliver F. Piattella&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Joras_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sergio E. Jor&amp;#xe1;s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;We investigate the linear regime of f(R) = R + alpha R^2 gravity for static,\nspherically symmetric and asymptotically flat configurations of matter. We show\nthat, in vacuum and deep inside the range of the extra scalar degree of\nfreedom, the post-Newtonian parameter gamma is not equal to 1/2, as established\nin the literature, but it assumes larger values depending on the pressure of\nthe star. We provide an explicit expression for gamma in terms of the mass, of\nthe integrated pressure of the star and of the ratio between the star&apos;s radius\nand the range of the extra degree of freedom. We corroborate our results by\nproviding numerical solutions for the case of a neutron star.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.01322</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>On local scale invariance and the questionable theoretical basis of the conformal transformations&apos; issue. (arXiv:1811.02458v2 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.02458</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Quiros_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Israel Quiros&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Arcia_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Roberto De Arcia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;Here we follow the mainstream of thinking about physical equivalence of\ndifferent representations of a theory, regarded as the consequence of\ninvariance of the laws of physics -- represented by an action principle and the\nderived motion equations -- under given transformations; be it coordinate,\ngauge or conformal transformations. Accordingly the conformal transformations&apos;\nissue is discussed by invoking the assumed invariance of the laws of physics --\nin particular the laws of gravity -- under conformal transformations of the\nmetric. It is shown that Brans-Dicke and scalar-tensor theories are not\nwell-suited to address physical equivalence of the conformal frames since the\ncorresponding laws of gravity are not invariant under the conformal\ntransformations or Weyl rescalings. The search for conformal symmetry leads us\nto explore the physical consequences of Weyl-invariant theories of gravity,\nthat represent a natural arena where to discuss on physical equivalence of the\nconformally related representations. We show that conformal invariance of the\naction of a (supposedly conformal invariant) theory and of the derived motion\nequations is not enough to ensure actual Weyl invariance. It is required, also,\nthat the underlying geometrical structure of the background spacetime be, at\nleast, Weyl-integrable. Otherwise, if assume (as usual) spacetimes of\n(pseudo)Riemannian geometrical structure, the resulting -- apparently conformal\ninvariant -- theory is anomalous in that, only massless matter fields can be\nconsistently coupled. Gauge freedom, a distinctive feature of actually\nWeyl-invariant theories of gravity, leads to very unusual consequences.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.02458</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>2-field model of dark energy with canonical and non-canonical kinetic terms. (arXiv:1811.03005v2 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.03005</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Sergijenko_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;O. Sergijenko&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;We generalize quintom to include the tachyonic kinetic term along with the\nclassical one. For such a model we obtain the expressions for energy density\nand pressure. For the spatially flat, homogeneous and isotropic Universe with\nFriedmann-Robertson-Walker metric of 4-space we derive the equations of motion\nfor the fields. We discuss in detail the reconstruction of the scalar fields\npotential $U(\\phi,\\xi)$. Such a reconstruction cannot be done unambiguously, so\nwe consider 3 simplest forms of $U(\\phi,\\xi)$: the product of $\\Phi(\\phi)$ and\n$\\Xi(\\xi)$, the sum of $\\Phi(\\phi)$ and $\\Xi(\\xi)$ and this sum to the\n$\\kappa$th power.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.03005</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>2+1D Loop Quantum Gravity on the Edge. (arXiv:1811.04360v2 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.04360</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Freidel_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Laurent Freidel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Girelli_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Florian Girelli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Shoshany_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Barak Shoshany&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;We develop a new perspective on the discretization of the phase space\nstructure of gravity in 2+1 dimensions as a piecewise-flat geometry in 2\nspatial dimensions. Starting from a subdivision of the continuum geometric and\nphase space structure into elementary cells, we obtain the loop gravity phase\nspace coupled to a collection of effective particles carrying mass and spin,\nwhich measure the curvature and torsion of the geometry. We show that the new\ndegrees of freedom associated to the particle-like elements can be understood\nas edge modes, which appear in the decomposition of the continuum theory into\nsubsystems and do not cancel out in the gluing of cells along codimension 2\ndefects. These new particle-like edge modes are gravitationally dressed in an\nexplicit way. This provides a detailed explanation of the relations and\ndifferences between the loop gravity phase space and the one deduced from the\ncontinuum theory.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.04360</guid>\n</item>\n<item>\n<title>Bose-Einstein Condensates as Gravitational Wave Detectors. (arXiv:1811.04468v1 [quant-ph] CROSS LISTED)</title>\n<link>http://fr.arxiv.org/abs/1811.04468</link>\n<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Robbins_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Matthew P. G. Robbins&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Afshordi_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Niayesh Afshordi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Mann_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Robert Mann&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n&lt;p&gt;We investigate a Bose-Einstein condensate (BEC) as a gravitational wave\ndetector, and study its sensitivity by optimizing the properties of the\ncondensate and the measurement duration. We show that detecting kilohertz\ngravitational waves is limited by current experimental techniques in squeezing\nBEC phonons, while at higher frequencies, decoherence due to phonon-phonon\ninteraction gives the main limitation. Future improvements in technology to\nsqueeze BEC states can make them competitive detectors for gravitational waves\nof astrophysical and/or cosmological origin.\n&lt;/p&gt;\n</description>\n<guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1811.04468</guid>\n</item>\n</channel>\n</rss>